<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Premierworks.org</title><link>http://rssenar.github.io/</link><description>A Personal Site on Technology &amp; Life</description><atom:link href="http://rssenar.github.io/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 May 2016 04:26:09 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>My Resume</title><link>http://rssenar.github.io/posts/my-resume/</link><dc:creator>Richard Senar</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;CONFIDENTIALITY REQUESTED AND APPRECIATED&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;RICHARD S. SENAR&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3219 Hannover Street, Corona, California 92882
Cell: (949) 373-5763 • Residence: (951) 278-9131
rssenar@gmail.com • www.github.com/rssenar
https://www.linkedin.com/in/richard-senar-91767713&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;DATA ANALYTICS CONSULTANT - PYTHON DEVELOPER - OPERATIONS / PROJECT MANAGER&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data Analytics Consultant with over 10 years of progressive experience in fast-moving, growth-oriented firms. Proven track record in strategic planning and implementation, focusing on overhauling outdated IT systems, turning around poor performing operations and guiding organizations through all phases of business development. Demonstrated skills in all aspects of operations including data management, new systems development, business forecasting and resource allocation. Major strengths in process development &amp;amp; improvement, custom software development/integration, marketing and customer service. BS, Business Administration, Computer Applications Systems Development Project Management Supervision.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Technical Proficiency&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Programming Languages: Python, Shell Scripting, JavaScript, SQL, HTML, CSS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Operating Systems: OSX Unix, MS Operating System (Windows XP)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software: Extensive knowledge in MS Office Suite (Word, Excel, Access, PowerPoint, Outlook), FIleMaker, Extensive knowledge in SAP Business Objects Postalsoft Desktop Mailer Software&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hardware: Knowledgeable in installation, configuration, diagnosing, preventive maintenance of windows workstations &amp;amp; laptops.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language Proficiencies: English, Tagalog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;EMPLOYMENT BACKGROUND AND ACCOMPLISHMENTS&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Premierworks Consultancy&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Corona, California (2012-Present)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Owner, Direct Marketing &amp;amp; Data Analytics consulting firm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interpret data, analyze results using statistical techniques and provide ongoing reports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop and implement data collection systems that optimize efficiency and data quality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide data from secondary data sources to supplement customer databases or augment marketing campaigns.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify, analyze, and interpret market trends or patterns in complex data sets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work closely with management to prioritize business needs and locate and define new process improvement opportunities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Help clients by refining their competitive edge through effective direct mail programs that compliment their sales force, adapt to their system, and maximize ROI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Genesis Automotive Marketing&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple Valley, California (2012-2014) Marketing firm specializing in automotive direct mail events&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Project Manager (2012-2014)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
Responsible for the back end operations of the company including but not limited to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensuring timely completion of all direct marketing events&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coordinating between clients and vendors with regarding to Sign-off, deliverables and payment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managed customer and client databases as well as generating pre and post event marketing analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managed day-to-day logistics pertaining to events and supplementary materials.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Spectrum Business Solutions&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Irvine, California (2004-2012) Marketing &amp;amp; direct mail consulting firm&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;General Manager (2008-2012)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
Responsible for developing, implementing and monitoring management operations systems. Managed restructuring of the Corporate Planning Group System, resulting in company savings and increased efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed, implemented and managed a web based training module program utilizing interactive screen captures with explanation boxes as well as audio commentary to generate a tutorial for the end user, resulting in vastly improved user comprehension and retention of complicated processes that simplified the education of new employees.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Streamlined day to day operations by implementing procedural changes and process improvements, resulting in increased efficiency and productivity enabling the company to venture into new business opportunities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented a file sharing network system that integrated all workstations to a central data storage center and instituted guidelines and protocols among users to improved workflow, resulting in reduced errors in data transfer and increase in user productivity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Led implementation and migration to new Database Management Software program including CASS certification and NCOA link functionality, resulting in a 30% decrease in overtime work and 50% decrease in returned mail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managed implementation of the Goldmine CRM system including upgrading the necessary hardware and partnering with hardware and software vendors to ensure a smooth implementation and training on the new system, resulting in successful CRM deployment in three weeks, significantly improving the way customers are managed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Operations / Data / IT Manager (2004-2008)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
Responsible for management and processing of customer database in direct mail processing. Updated Legacy Database Management Systems and designed and planned company infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented a file sharing network system that integrated all workstations to a central data storage center and instituted guidelines and protocols among users to improved workflow, resulting in reduced errors in data transfer and increase in user productivity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Led implementation and migration to new Database Management Software program including CASS certification and NCOA link functionality, resulting in a 30% decrease in overtime work and 50% decrease in returned mail.
Database / Operations / IT Manager &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turned around mail production crisis when mail production equipment became suddenly inoperative by reorganizing
production crew into teams to collaborate with available off-site vendor while transplanting company mail operation
to the vendor site, resulting in delivery of 50,000 pieces of mail on schedule and diffusing the crisis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developed a bar-coded mail tracking system utilizing off the shelf hardware and software for ease of implementation,
resulting in increased speed and efficiency to process walk-in customers leading to improved customer service.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Graphics Designer (2004)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
Responsible for the conceptualization of new thematic schemes for direct mail promotional materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Spa De Soleil&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sun Valley, California (2003-2004)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contract manufacturer that produces a wide range of health and beauty aids, cosmetics and toiletries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Operations &amp;amp; Customer Service Officer (2003-2004)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
Responsible for management of incoming &amp;amp; outgoing shipping requirements and supervision of day to day equipment sales operations. Handled customer service concerns for Equipment Department including inventory and equipment repairs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Globe Telecom, Inc.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mandaluyong City, Philippines (1999-2001)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Provider of telecommunication services and equipment and telecommunication infrastructure development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Customer Service Officer (2000-2001)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
Responsible for supervising day-to-day center operations including customer handling, sales transactions and after sales transactions. Designated Line Trainer providing staff training on new policies and procedures to be implemented in the business center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Visual Graphic Designer (1999-2000)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
Responsible for supervising implementation of visual and graphical merchandise for Globe Telecom business centers such as posters, brochures and other printed material. Created a manual for the standardization of merchandise materials for the business centers. Provided for conceptualization of new thematic schemes for promotional merchandising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Created and developed the Global Omnibus Theme campaign by collaborating with other departments to ensure consistent implementation while working closely with management to guarantee the concept was in line with the company vision, resulting in successful implementation in 20 business centers to rave reviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Education&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BS, Information Technology - DeVry University, Pomona, California, Magna Cum Laude&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BS in Business Administration, Computer Applications - De La Salle University - College of St. Benilde, Manila, Philippines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://rssenar.github.io/posts/my-resume/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2016 04:25:12 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>